Mohammed Faizal,

Mobile: +971 543478423 Mail Id – paiju.s@gmail.com

Personnel Details.

Date of Birth 3rd June 1987

Gender Male
Marital Status Married
Nationality Indian
Passport No U2995919

Driving License Yes, (Holding a Saudi & Indian, light vehicle license).

Career Objective.

An ambitious, creative and highly motivated individual with an uncompromising commitment to quality and outstanding service. Comprehensive management, planning and support service to all the staff. Seeking a role in Administration, where my 9 years of administrative experience will contribute promising results to the firm and provide the potential for professional career development.

Skills and Proficiencies.

Leadership, Conflict Management, Business Negotiation,

Decision-Making, People Management

Data Entry Skills, Data Processing Skills, Dependable Reporting Skills, Deadline-Oriented, Budget Development

Critical Thinking and Problem-Solving Skills

Planning and Organizing, Communication Skills, Persuasiveness

Influencing and Leading, Teamwork, Adaptability and Stress Tolerance

Professional Experience.

Feb 2017 – Present Business Development Executive for Fame Associates, India.

Work Details Project management and supervising and coordinating work of staff & external third

parties. Prioritizing customer requirements and defining the Vision.

Responsible for proposing overall budget, delivering monthly revenue forecasts.

Planning, directing and coordinating various aspects of the business.

Chase up new business opportunities.

Proven ability to grow a business.

Maintaining relationships with key clients.

Increasing brand awareness and bringing in new customers.

Making sure that operations run smoothly and according to company policy.

Oct 2013 - Dec 2016

Operations coordinator for Rawasi Trading Company, Dammam/Jubail. KSA

Work Details

Assisting with the management of daily operational activities.

Performing administrative tasks, such as making travel arrangements, answering phones, scheduling meetings, etc.

Managing office supplies and the maintenance of office equipment.

Coordinating the proper allocation of human resources.

Arranging and assisting with the on boarding of new employees.

Assisting with project management by creating assignments, tracking progress, and resolving issues.

Managing internal and external stakeholder relations.

Managing budgets and preparing financial reports for senior management.

Planning and organizing conferences, events, staff training, and employee engagement activities.

Preparing and maintaining operations documents and reports.

Feb 2012 – July 2013

Administrative coordinator for Well Care Trading and Contracting Co, Al Hassa

Work Details

Effective communicator, Practices good judgment and discretion while working closely with sales managers, firm's internal departments and customers.

Hiring, supervising, and evaluating staff members.

Assisting with special projects, such as process improvements and budget development.

Multi-task effectively, prioritize independently and meet tight deadlines at all costs.

Equally efficient off and on site, Proficient in PowerPoint, Excel and Word.

Developed and sustained relationships with potential and existing clients by coordinating professional meetings and providing effective administrative support.

Handled Sales and contact with Government & Semi Government like Armaco, Sabic, Petro Rabig and Seeco

Responsible for timely, accurate quotations and various pro-forma invoices to customers, processing inquires through personal visits, email, phone and fax.

Meet with customers on and off company premises for discussions.

Made efficient purchases resale supplies.

Jun 2009 - Feb 2012

Airline Ticketing Staff, Suhana Travels, India.

Work Details

Solid understanding of International Air Transport Association regulations.

Proficient in common airline booking software and database management.

Comprehensive experience with handling multiple booking issues.

Capable of working multiple shifts including evenings and weekends.

Able to meet tight booking deadlines in a timely manner.

Good communications and problem-solving skills.

Worked to diligently resolve booking and scheduling issues. Ensure that all booking procedures followed industry standards.

Posted schedule changes online and informed clients directly.

Scheduled advance and last-minute bookings.

Offered discounts and special deals when authorized to do so Managed passenger database.

Monitored airline schedules and posted updates on airline website

Developed and implemented promotional strategies to boost airline bookings.

Consistently offered a high level of customer service and Worked to resolved passenger booking issues.

Handled internal and external communications.

Jan 2009 - July 2009 Joined as a Trainee, Akbar Travels of India. Mangalore.

Work Details Understanding of International Air Transport Association regulations.

Trained in Amadeus & Galileo airline booking software and database management.

Qualification

March 2005 Passed Pre-University College from Anjuman Per University College.

April 2008 Graduated from Sri Devi College of Information and Technology (Affiliated to

Mangalore University).

Nov 2008 IATA from Globe Collage of Travel & Tourism Mangalore

Languages English fluent

Hindi fluent

Arabic intermediate

Declaration.

I hereby declare that the above given information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.